<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
 xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<front/>
		<body/>
		<back>
<listBibl>
	<bibl><author>witness PW2 Sh. Jagmohan Sharma</author>, from the office of the local electricity company/BSES. <title level="a">Appellant/defendant however, failed to lead his evidence and his evidence was closed by the Order dated 22.8.2013. These aspects are noted in paras 6 to 8 of the judgment of the trial court and which read as under:-&quot;(6) The plaintiff examined herself as PW1 to prove her case. She reiterated the facts stated in the plaint. She relied upon the following documents</title>. (a) Ex.<note>PW-1/1 to Ex. PW 1/8 are photographs indicating the &quot;Kainchi gate&quot; at point A</note>;</bibl>
	<bibl>(b) Ex.<note>PW 1/9 is receipt of Jeevan Citizen Service Center run by the plaintiff at her premises</note>;</bibl>
	<bibl>(c) Ex.<title level="a">PW 1/10 is the copy of electricity bill in the name of Sh</title>. <title level="j">Kuljeet Singh</title>, of period from <idno>10.11.2005 to 13.01</idno>.<date>2016</date> <note>indicated at point X pertaining to property of plaintiff in the suit premises</note>;</bibl>
	<bibl>(d) Ex. <title level="a">PW 1/11 is the copy of electricity bill in the name of the plaintiff pertaining to the period</title> <date>March</date>, <date>2008</date>;</bibl>
	<bibl>(e) Ex. <note>PW 1/12 is the electricity bill in the name of Kuljeet Singh of CRN No. 2510114324 (previous owner of property i.e. basement) of plaintiff</note>;</bibl>
	<bibl>(f) Ex. <idno>PW 1/13</idno> <title level="a">(colly) is name changed demand notice to the plaintiff dated 30.10.2010 in respect of electricity meter bearing K No. 2511 N 8031735 from Sh</title>. <note>Kuljeet Singh in her name</note>;</bibl>
	<bibl>(g) Ex. <title level="a">PW 1/14 is a site plan of the suit property i.e. the ground floor highlight the common area from point</title> A, <pubPlace>B, C and D</pubPlace>;</bibl>
	<bibl>(h) <title level="a">Ex PW 1/15 (colly) are two complaints made to the police by the plaintiff dated 21.05</title>.<date>2011 and 24.05.2011</date>;</bibl>
	<bibl>(i) Ex. <note>PW 1/16 (colly-24 pages</note>) <title level="s">are the copies of registered GPA with consideration from previous owner i.e. Sh. <title level="a">Kuljeet Singh to the plaintiff and previous chain of property papers of basement property of the plaintiff. (7) The plaintiff has also examined Mr. Jagmohan Sharma, Section Officer, BSES Office, Pul Prahaladpur, New Delhi, as PW2. He has produced summoned record. The entire file including requisite documents for change of name along with check list and acknowledgement of DSS request order for change of name from</title> <note>Kuljeet Singh to Shobha Shukla duly certified are</note></bibl>

		</listBibl>
	</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
