<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
			<front>CRL.L.P. 258/2018 <lb/>Page 1 of 4 <lb/>* <lb/>IN THE HIGH COURT OF DELHI AT NEW DELHI <lb/>% <lb/>Decided on: 20 th April, 2018 <lb/>+ <lb/>CRL.L.P. 258/2018 <lb/>M/S. APS FOREX SERVICES PVT. LTD. <lb/>..... Petitioner <lb/>Represented by: Mr. Varinder Kumar Sharma <lb/>and Ms. Parul Sharma, <lb/>Advocates <lb/>versus <lb/>SHAKTI INTERNATIONAL FASHION <lb/>LINKERS &amp; ORS <lb/>..... Respondent <lb/>Represented by: None <lb/>CORAM: <lb/>HON&apos;BLE MS. JUSTICE MUKTA GUPTA <lb/>MUKTA GUPTA, J. (ORAL) <lb/>Crl.M.A. 7279/2018 (Exemption) <lb/>Allowed, subject to all just exception. <lb/>Crl.M.A. 7278/2018 <lb/>For the reasons stated in the application, delay of 62 days in filing the <lb/>leave to appeal petition is condoned. <lb/>Application is disposed of. <lb/>CRL.L.P. 258/2018 <lb/>1. <lb/>Petitioner (APS Forex Services Pvt. Ltd.) filed complaint case no. <lb/>613773/16 under Section 138 Negotiable Instruments Act, 1881 (in short &apos;NI <lb/>Act&apos;) alleging that in discharge of liability arising out of issuance of foreign <lb/>exchange/USD card under LERM scheme vide request letters dated 10th <lb/>Januray, 2014, 20th February, 2014 and 22nd February, 2014, respondent <lb/>no. 1 (Shakti International Fashion Linkers) issued four cheques totaling to <lb/>CRL.L.P. 258/2018 <lb/></front>

			<page>Page 2 of 4 <lb/></page>

			<body>Rs.12,55,513/-which were dishonored. When the aforesaid fact was brought <lb/>to the knowledge of the respondent, fresh cheque bearing no. 374941 dated <lb/>31st May, 2014 for a sum of Rs.9,55,574/-drawn on Oriental Bank of <lb/>Commerce, Defence Colony Branch, New Delhi was issued. Aforesaid <lb/>cheque was also returned unpaid vide memo dated 2nd June, 2014 with <lb/>remarks &apos;Stop Payment&apos;. Petitioner issued a legal notice dated 10th June, <lb/>2014 through registered post but the respondent failed to make the payment. <lb/>Hence, the present complaint. <lb/>2. <lb/>To prove the case, authorized signatory of petitioner examined <lb/>himself as CW-1 and tendered his evidence by way of an affidavit as <lb/>Ex.CW-1/2 and also exhibited request letters dated 10th January, 2014, 20th <lb/>February, 2014 and 22nd February, 2014 as Ex.CW-1/D, Ex.CW-1/E and <lb/>Ex.CW-1/F respectively, letter dated 22nd February, 2014 as Ex.CW-1/G, <lb/>invoice no. 9865 as Ex. CW-1/I, invoice no. 10020 as Ex.CW-1/K, invoice <lb/>no. 10021 as Ex.CW-1/L, original cheque as Ex.CW-1/M, cheque returning <lb/>memo as Ex.CW-1/O and legal demand notice as Ex.CW-1/P. During his <lb/>cross-examination, the petitioner proved his statement of ledger account as <lb/>Ex.CW-1/T (colly), bank statement as Ex. CW-1/U (colly), details of <lb/>debtors and creditors as Ex. CW-1/D2, service tax details as Ex.CW-1/D3 <lb/>(colly), statement of travel card as Ex.CW-1/D6 and list of sundry creditors <lb/>as Ex.CW-1/D7. <lb/>3. <lb/>Sushil Kumar, partner of respondent no. 1, in his statement recorded <lb/>under Section 313 Cr.P.C. stated that he was the signatory to the cheque and <lb/>the cheque was issued as blank security cheque wherein the amount was <lb/>filed by the petitioner. He further submitted that the request letters were <lb/>forged and fabricated. He also submitted that the cards, for which payment <lb/></body>

			<note place="headnote">CRL.L.P. 258/2018 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 3 of 4 <lb/></page>

			<listBibl>was sought, were not issued by respondent no. 1. <lb/>4. <lb/>Anuj Sharma, respondent no. 2, in his statement recorded under <lb/>Section 313 Cr.P.C. stated that he was also a partner of respondent no. 1 and <lb/>took the same stand as Sushil Kumar. <lb/>5. <lb/>Respondents did not lead any defence evidence. <lb/>6. <lb/>It is the case of the petitioner that Sushil Kumar approached the <lb/>Petitioner for issuance of foreign exchange/USD card under LERM Scheme <lb/>vide request letters dated 10th January, 2014, 20th February, 2014 and 22nd <lb/>February, 2014. Petitioner had issued USD card of 15,000/-amounting to <lb/>Rs. 9,45,746/-vide invoice no. 9865 dated 10th January, 2014, travel card of <lb/>$10,000 amounting to Rs.6,35,554/-vide invoice no. 9993 dated 20th <lb/>February, 2014, foreign exchange of USD (CN) 2500 amounting to <lb/>Rs.1,60,010/-vide invoice no. 10020 dated 22nd February, 2014 and foreign <lb/>exchange of USD (CN) 2500 amounting to Rs.1,60,010/-vide invoice no. <lb/>10021 dated 22nd February, 2014. Aforesaid transactions totaled to Rs. <lb/>19,01,320/-, out of which part payment was made by the respondent firm of <lb/>Rs. 6,45,307/-. In discharge of the foresaid liability, cheque for a sum of Rs. <lb/>9,55,574/-was issued. <lb/>7. <lb/></listBibl>

			<body>From the documents placed on record, it is evident that USD card for <lb/>a sum of 15,000/-was issued on 10th January, 2014, however, the travel for <lb/>the card was allegedly issued to commence from 8th January, 2014. The bill <lb/>was not raised in the name of individual traveller and the USD card reached <lb/>the traveller who would have already reached his destination on the day <lb/>when the bill was raised. How the USD card reached the traveller who <lb/>would have been already at the destination was not explained. USD card <lb/>issued to the traveller on 10th January, 2014 against the ticket of scheduled <lb/></body>

			<note place="headnote">CRL.L.P. 258/2018 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 4 of 4 <lb/></page>

			<div type="annex">travel of 8th January, 2014 was also not explained. Thus, the issuance of <lb/>USD card of 15,000/-against request letter dated 10th January, 2014 was <lb/>doubtful. <lb/>8. <lb/>Furthermore, the petitioner failed to produce vouchers containing <lb/>acknowledgement of receipt of two transactions of foreign exchange of USD <lb/>(CN) 2500 dated 22nd February, 2014. With respect to the transaction <lb/>pertaining to issuance of travel card of $10,000 amounting to Rs.6,35,554/-<lb/>vide invoice no. 9993 dated 20th February, 2014, the amount actually <lb/>withdrawn therefrom was not proved. Though the petitioner produced the <lb/>statement of account of travel card Ex.CW-1/D6, however, the same was <lb/>neither proved in terms of Bankers&apos; Book Evidence Act,1891 nor <lb/>accompanied by certificate under section 65B of Indian Evidence Act, 1872, <lb/>thus inadmissible in evidence. <lb/>9. <lb/>Considering the evidence on record, the learned Trial Court rightly <lb/>held that the petitioner failed to prove that there was any legal liability of the <lb/>respondents to pay the cheque amount and dismissed the complaint, thereby <lb/>acquitting the respondents. Finding of the learned Trial Court is neither <lb/>illegal nor perverse warranting interference. <lb/>10. Leave to appeal petition is dismissed. <lb/>(MUKTA GUPTA) <lb/>JUDGE <lb/>APRIL 20, 2018 <lb/>&apos;ga&apos; </div>


	</text>
</tei>
