<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
			<note place="headnote">W.P.(C) 8137/2018 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 1 of 3 <lb/></page>

			<body>#58 <lb/>IN THE HIGH COURT OF DELHI AT NEW DELHI <lb/>Judgment delivered on: 06.08.2018 <lb/>W.P.(C) 8137/2018 <lb/>RAMESH HALDAR <lb/>..... Petitioner <lb/>versus <lb/>EAST DELHI MUNICIPAL CORPORATION ..... Respondent <lb/>Advocates who appeared in this case: <lb/>For the Petitioner <lb/>: Mr. Prashant Sharma and Mr. Amit Kumar Verma, Advocates <lb/>For the Respondent <lb/>: Mr. G.D. Mishra, Advocate <lb/>CORAM: <lb/>HON&apos;BLE MR. JUSTICE SIDDHARTH MRIDUL <lb/>J U D G M E N T <lb/>SIDDHARTH MRIDUL, J (ORAL) <lb/>1. <lb/>The present petition under Article 226 of the Constitution of India <lb/>prays as follows:-<lb/>&quot;In the facts and circumstances of the present case this <lb/>Hon&apos;ble Court may pleased to: <lb/></body>

			<note place="headnote">W.P.(C) 8137/2018 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 2 of 3 <lb/></page>

			<body>a) Pass a writ of mandamus or any other appropriate <lb/>writ/order(s)/direction(s) against the respondent, thereby <lb/>directing or ordering the respondent to allow a period of <lb/>15 days to the petitioner to remove his machines, <lb/>raw/furnished material out of the premises so sealed by <lb/>the respondent i.e. premises bearing Plot No.6, C <lb/>Extension Block, New Ashok Nagar, Delhi-110096. <lb/>b) Any other relief may also be granted by the Hon&apos;ble Court <lb/>in favour of the petitioner as well as against the <lb/>respondent.&quot; <lb/>2. <lb/>Notice. <lb/>3. <lb/>Mr. G.D. Mishra, learned counsel accepts notice on behalf of the <lb/>respondent. <lb/>4. <lb/>Mr. Prashant Sharma, learned counsel appearing on behalf of the <lb/>petitioner limits the relief in the present petition to a direction to the East <lb/>Delhi Municipal Corporation, the respondent herein, to consider his <lb/>application seeking permission to remove his goods and belongings from the <lb/>subject premises bearing Plot No.6, C Extension Block, New Ashok Nagar, <lb/>Delhi-110096, that are lying sealed. <lb/>5. <lb/>Learned counsel appearing on behalf of EDMC states that if a <lb/>representation is received in this behalf from the petitioner, the same shall be <lb/>disposed of, in accordance with law, within a period of two weeks thereafter, <lb/>under intimation to the petitioner. <lb/></body>

			<note place="headnote">W.P.(C) 8137/2018 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 3 of 3 <lb/></page>

			<body>6. <lb/>With the above directions, the writ petition is disposed of. <lb/>SIDDHARTH MRIDUL <lb/>(JUDGE) <lb/>AUGUST 06, 2018 <lb/>dn </body>


	</text>
</tei>
