<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
			<front>W.P.(C) 398/2017 <lb/>Page 1 of 2 <lb/>* <lb/>IN THE HIGH COURT OF DELHI AT NEW DELHI <lb/>Date of Order: August 30, 2018 <lb/>+ <lb/>W.P.(C) 8684/2018 <lb/>SUDESH BALA <lb/>..... Petitioner <lb/>Through: Mr. Deepak Khosla, Advocate <lb/>Versus <lb/>GOVT OF NCT DELHI &amp; ANR. <lb/>..... Respondents <lb/>Through: Mr. Yeeshu Jain, Standing Counsel <lb/>with Ms.Jyoti Tyagi, Advocate <lb/>CORAM: <lb/>HON&apos;BLE MR. JUSTICE SUNIL GAUR <lb/></front>

			<body>ORDER <lb/>(ORAL) <lb/>1. <lb/>Impugned order of 16 th October, 2017 (Annexure P-1) rejects <lb/>petitioner&apos;s application for allotment of alternate plot in lieu of acquired <lb/>land on the ground that the following requisite documents have not been <lb/>furnished:-<lb/>(i). Affidavit <lb/>(ii). Complete revenue record <lb/>(iii). Ownership status <lb/>(iv). R.D.(Relinquishment Deed) <lb/>2. <lb/>Counsel for petitioner submits that on the last date of hearing, copy <lb/>of Minutes of Meeting of the Recommendation Committee held on 17 th <lb/>September, 2014 was handed over to respondents&apos; counsel to clarify as to <lb/>how the impugned order can be justified, as the Recommendation <lb/>Committee had recommended the case of petitioner for allotment of <lb/>alternate plot way back in the year 2014. <lb/></body>

			<note place="headnote">W.P.(C) 398/2017 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 2 of 2 <lb/></page>

			<body>3. <lb/>On behalf of respondent, it is maintained that the requisite <lb/>documents, as afore-noted, have not been supplied and therefore, the <lb/>competent authority has rejected the case of petitioner. On the other hand, <lb/>petitioner&apos;s counsel maintains that aforesaid documents were appended to <lb/>the application seeking allotment of alternate plot. <lb/>4. <lb/>Without going into this aspect any further, it is deemed appropriate <lb/>to dispose of this petition with direction to respondent to reconsider <lb/>petitioner&apos;s application (Annexure P-3) after the aforesaid documents are <lb/>supplied by petitioner within three weeks from today. Upon receipt of <lb/>such documents, petitioner&apos;s application (Annexure P-3) be considered <lb/>by respondent within twelve weeks and its fate be made known to <lb/>petitioner within three weeks thereafter, so that petitioner may avail of the <lb/>remedies, as available in law, if need be. <lb/>5. <lb/>With aforesaid directions, this petition is disposed of. <lb/>(SUNIL GAUR) <lb/>JUDGE <lb/>AUGUST 30, 2018 <lb/>r </body>


	</text>
</tei>
