<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
			<front>RSA No.236/2016 <lb/>Page 1 of 6 <lb/>* <lb/>IN THE HIGH COURT OF DELHI AT NEW DELHI <lb/>+ <lb/>RSA 236/2016 &amp; CM Nos. 30418-30419/2016 <lb/>% <lb/>1 st September, 2016 <lb/>SOHAN LAL <lb/>..... Appellant <lb/>Through: Mr. Arun Kaushal, Advocate <lb/>Versus <lb/>SOBHA SHUKLA <lb/>..... Respondent <lb/>CORAM: <lb/>HON&apos;BLE MR. JUSTICE VALMIKI J.MEHTA <lb/>To be referred to the Reporter or not? <lb/>VALMIKI J. MEHTA, J (ORAL) <lb/>1. <lb/>This Regular Second Appeal filed under Section 100 of the Code of <lb/>Civil Procedure, 1908 (CPC) impugns the concurrent Judgments of the courts <lb/></front>

			<body>below; of the Trial Court dated 13.4.2015 and the First Appellate Court dated <lb/>3.5.2016; by which the courts below have decreed the suit filed by the <lb/>respondent/plaintiff for permanent and mandatory injunction. Operative <lb/>paragraph 30 of the judgment of the trial court decreeing the suit reads as <lb/>under:-<lb/>&quot;In the light of discussion hereinabove, suit of the plaintiff is decreed. The <lb/>defendant is hereby restrained from constructing any staircases at the back <lb/>portion of the property bearing no. 277/7, Ground Floor, Pul Prahaladpur, New <lb/>Delhi. The defendant is also hereby restrained from blocking and locking the <lb/>common passage entrance gate and bathroom at the ground floor of the above <lb/>said property. The defendant is further restrained from creating any hindrance <lb/>in the use of common passage and bath room by the plaintiff in any manner on <lb/>the ground floor of the above said property. The defendant is also decreed to <lb/></body>

			<note place="headnote">RSA No.236/2016 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 2 of 6 <lb/></page>

			<body>remove the goods kept by him in the common passage at the ground floor of <lb/>the above said property. In the circumstances of the case, no order for cost. <lb/>Parties shall bear their own cost.&quot; <lb/>(underlining added) <lb/>2. <lb/>The case of the respondent/plaintiff was that she purchased the <lb/>basement/lower ground floor of the property bearing No. 277/7, Pul <lb/>Prahaladpur, New Delhi, as per documentation dated 26.10.2005 from Sh. <lb/>Kuljeet Singh. The title documents included registered General Power of <lb/>Attorney, agreement to sell, affidavit etc. By these documents proved as <lb/>Ex.PW1/16 (colly) before the trial court, respondent/plaintiff purchased rights in <lb/>the suit property along with common passage for approach, staircase etc. The <lb/>respondent/plaintiff was enjoying the common passage, staircase and bathroom <lb/>on the ground floor since the date of purchase of the suit property and the <lb/>respondent/plaintiff had installed entrance gate and the door at the back portion <lb/>of the common passage with the joint funds with other shopkeepers for safety <lb/>purpose. Electricity meter of the respondent/plaintiff was also installed at the <lb/>common passage of the ground floor of the suit property. That the <lb/>appellant/defendant has wilfully and illegally blocked the common passage by <lb/>keeping his almirah and table and he also has locked the bathroom. <lb/>Appellant/defendant was seeking to create hindrance in the use of the common <lb/>passage, and also the bathroom and was trying to illegally put locks at the <lb/>ground floor of the suit property. Appellant/defendant was also illegally trying <lb/>to build the staircase on the back portion of the suit property, therefore, closing <lb/>the door of the back portion as well as the window of the basement property of <lb/></body>

			<note place="headnote">RSA No.236/2016 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 3 of 6 <lb/></page>

			<body>the respondent/plaintiff. <lb/>he subject suit hence was filed by the <lb/>respondent/plaintiff with the following prayers:-<lb/>&quot;(a) pass a decree of permanent injunction in favour of the plaintiff by <lb/>restraining the defendants, their agents, associates, legal heirs etc. from <lb/>constructing the staircase at back portion of the said property and blocking and <lb/>locking the common passage entrance gate and bathroom at the ground floor of <lb/>the suit property and not to interfere in the use of common passage and <lb/>bathroom by the plaintiff in any manner. <lb/>(b) Pass a decree of mandatory injunction in favour of the plaintiff and against <lb/>the defendant by removing the goods kept by the defendant in the common <lb/>passage at the ground floor. <lb/>(c) Cost of the suit be awarded in favour of the plaintiff and against the <lb/>defendant. <lb/>(d) Any other relief (s) this Hon&quot;ble Court may deems fit and proper in the <lb/>facts and circumstances in the present case.&quot; <lb/>3. <lb/>Appellant/defendant filed his written statement and denied the <lb/>rights of the respondent/plaintiff in the common passage or the bathroom or in <lb/>the back portion. It was pleaded that the respondent/plaintiff had no rights in <lb/>the common passage or the back portion or the bathroom of the ground floor of <lb/>the property. <lb/>4. <lb/>After pleadings were completed, the trial court on 12.9.2011 framed the <lb/>following issues:-<lb/>&quot;(1) Whether the suit is bad for mis-joinder on necessary parties? OPD <lb/>(2) Whether the suit is barred by delay and latches? OPD <lb/>(3) Whether the plaintiff has not approached the Court with clean <lb/>hand? OPD <lb/>(4) Whether the plaintiff is entitled to a decree of permanent injunction as <lb/>prayed for in prayer clause (a) of the plaint? OPD <lb/>(5) Whether the plaintiff is entitled to a decree of mandatory injunction as <lb/>prayed for in prayer clause (b) of the plaint? OPD <lb/></body>

			<note place="headnote">RSA No.236/2016 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 4 of 6 <lb/></page>

			<listBibl>(6) Relief. &quot; <lb/>5. <lb/>Evidence was led by the plaintiff as PW1 proving certain <lb/>documents besides also summoning witness PW2 Sh. Jagmohan Sharma, from <lb/>the office of the local electricity company/BSES. Appellant/defendant however, <lb/>failed to lead his evidence and his evidence was closed by the Order dated <lb/>22.8.2013. These aspects are noted in paras 6 to 8 of the judgment of the trial <lb/>court and which read as under:-<lb/>&quot;(6) The plaintiff examined herself as PW1 to prove her case. She reiterated <lb/>the facts stated in the plaint. She relied upon the following documents. <lb/>(a) Ex.PW-1/1 to Ex. PW 1/8 are photographs indicating the &quot;Kainchi gate&quot; at <lb/>point A; <lb/>(b) Ex.PW 1/9 is receipt of Jeevan Citizen Service Center run by the plaintiff <lb/>at her premises; <lb/>(c) Ex.PW 1/10 is the copy of electricity bill in the name of Sh. Kuljeet Singh, <lb/>of period from 10.11.2005 to 13.01.2016 indicated at point X pertaining to <lb/>property of plaintiff in the suit premises; <lb/>(d) Ex. PW 1/11 is the copy of electricity bill in the name of the plaintiff <lb/>pertaining to the period March, 2008; <lb/>(e) Ex. PW 1/12 is the electricity bill in the name of Kuljeet Singh of CRN No. <lb/>2510114324 (previous owner of property i.e. basement) of plaintiff; <lb/>(f) Ex. PW 1/13 (colly) is name changed demand notice to the plaintiff dated <lb/>30.10.2010 in respect of electricity meter bearing K No. 2511 N 8031735 from <lb/>Sh. Kuljeet Singh in her name; <lb/>(g) Ex. PW 1/14 is a site plan of the suit property i.e. the ground floor highlight <lb/>the common area from point A, B, C and D; <lb/>(h) Ex PW 1/15 (colly) are two complaints made to the police by the plaintiff <lb/>dated 21.05.2011 and 24.05.2011; <lb/>(i) Ex. PW 1/16 (colly-24 pages) are the copies of registered GPA with <lb/>consideration from previous owner i.e. Sh. Kuljeet Singh to the plaintiff and <lb/>previous chain of property papers of basement property of the plaintiff. <lb/>(7) The plaintiff has also examined Mr. Jagmohan Sharma, Section Officer, <lb/>BSES Office, Pul Prahaladpur, New Delhi, as PW2. He has produced <lb/>summoned record. The entire file including requisite documents for change of <lb/>name along with check list and acknowledgement of DSS request order for <lb/>change of name from Kuljeet Singh to Shobha Shukla duly certified are <lb/></listBibl>

			<note place="headnote">RSA No.236/2016 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 5 of 6 <lb/></page>

			<body>exhibited as Ex. PW2/A (colly-16 pages). <lb/>(8) PE was closed vide order dated 31.07.2013. The defendant did not lead any <lb/>evidence. DE was closed vide order dated 22.08.2013.&quot; <lb/>6. <lb/>The courts below have held that respondent/plaintiff by means of her <lb/>title documents Ex.PW1/16 (colly) has proved that respondent/plaintiff <lb/>purchased besides the basement/lower ground floor, right in the common <lb/>passage, staircase etc, and therefore, respondent/plaintiff had rights to use the <lb/>common passage, bathroom on the ground floor as also prevent the <lb/>appellant/defendant from closing the back door and construct the staircase at the <lb/>back. <lb/>7. <lb/>In my opinion, no substantial question of law arises under Section <lb/>100 CPC for setting aside of the concurrent judgments of courts below <lb/>inasmuch as whereas the respondent/plaintiff proved her case by leading <lb/>evidence, the appellant/defendant admittedly led no evidence. <lb/>8. <lb/>As also stated above, the title documents of the <lb/>respondent/plaintiff, Ex.PW1/16 (colly) duly show right of the <lb/>respondent/plaintiff besides to the basement also to the staircase and common <lb/>passage etc. The only way this evidence could be displaced was by leading of <lb/>evidence by the appellant/defendant with respect to whether he was the <lb/>exclusive owner of the common passage on the ground floor, bathroom on the <lb/>ground floor as also the back portion area for construction of the staircase, but <lb/>since appellant/defendant led no evidence, appellant/defendant cannot be said to <lb/></body>

			<note place="headnote">RSA No.236/2016 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 6 of 6 <lb/></page>

			<body>have proved his case of his ownership of the common passage, bathroom, back <lb/>portion etc. <lb/>9. <lb/>Learned counsel for the appellant/defendant argued that <lb/>appellant/defendant had moved an application before the first appellate court for <lb/>leading additional evidence under Order XLI Rule 27 CPC, but this application <lb/>was illegally not decided by the first appellate court, however I note that right to <lb/>lead additional evidence under Order XLI Rule 27 CPC is only if there is <lb/>already some evidence of a person and additional evidence is sought to be led <lb/>on complying with the ingredients of Order XLI Rule 27 CPC. However, once <lb/>evidence of a person is closed because evidence is not led in spite of sufficient <lb/>opportunities, then in such a case, the provision of Order XLI Rule 27 CPC <lb/>cannot be invoked. <lb/>10. <lb/>I must finally note that even before this Court in spite of <lb/>opportunities, appellant/defendant did not file copies of his title documents to <lb/>show that he was the exclusive owner of the ground floor, common passage, <lb/>bathroom on the ground floor or the back portion of the property. <lb/>11. <lb/>In view of the above, there is no merit in this Regular Second <lb/>Appeal and the same is therefore dismissed as no sufficient question of law <lb/>arises. <lb/>SEPTEMBER 01, 2016 <lb/>VALMIKI J. MEHTA, J <lb/>P </body>


	</text>
</tei>
