<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<tei xml:space="preserve">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc xml:id="0"/>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
			<front>ARB. P. 545/2018 <lb/>Page 1 of 3 <lb/>$~8 <lb/>* <lb/>IN THE HIGH COURT OF DELHI AT NEW DELHI <lb/>Date of decision: 04.12.2018 <lb/>+ <lb/>ARB.P. 545/2018 <lb/>PALLAVI FIRMS &amp; NURSERIES <lb/>..... Petitioner <lb/>Through <lb/>Dr. Kedarnath Tripathy and Mr. <lb/>B.B. Pradhan, Advs. <lb/>versus <lb/>NATIONAL SEEDS CORPORATION LIMITED ..... Respondent <lb/>Through <lb/>Mr. Yashvardhan, Ms. Smita Kant, <lb/>Mr. Abhishek Praharaj and Mr. <lb/>Puneet Kumar, Advs. <lb/>CORAM: <lb/>HON&apos;BLE MR. JUSTICE RAJIV SHAKDHER <lb/>RAJIV SHAKDHER, J.: (ORAL) <lb/>I.A. 16517/2018 <lb/></front>

			<body>1. <lb/>This is an application for seeking condonation of delay in filing <lb/>the reply. <lb/>1.1 The period of delay is 13 days. <lb/>1.2 For the reasons given in the application, the delay is condoned. <lb/>2. <lb/>The Registry will place the reply on record. <lb/>3. <lb/>The application is, accordingly, disposed of. <lb/></body>

			<note place="headnote">ARB. P. 545/2018 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 2 of 3 <lb/></page>

			<body>ARB.P. 545/2018 <lb/>4. <lb/>Notice in this petition was issued on 31.7.2018 which was made <lb/>returnable on 10.10.2018. <lb/>4.1 On 10.10.2018, learned counsel for the respondent was granted <lb/>ten (10) days to file a reply. <lb/>4.2 As noted hereinabove, the reply is under objection and not on <lb/>record. <lb/>4.3 The reason, perhaps, was that the reply was filed beyond the <lb/>period allocated by this Court vide order dated 10.10.2018. However, <lb/>counsel for the respondent, on being queried, says that the respondent&apos;s <lb/>principal objection to the arbitration petition is that the claim which is <lb/>sought to be placed before the Arbitral Tribunal is barred by limitation. <lb/>4.4 Learned counsel for the respondent, however, says that there is no <lb/>dispute as regards the existence of an arbitration agreement. <lb/>5 <lb/>I may only note that counsel for the petitioner says that the claim <lb/>is within the period of limitation. <lb/>5.1 This argument is articulated on the basis that the agreement <lb/>between the parties was executed on 14.6.2013, whereupon, supplies of <lb/>paddy and lentils were made. <lb/>5.2 The claim of the petitioner emanates from the alleged withholding <lb/>of amounts against the supplies made. <lb/>5.3 It is the petitioner&apos;s case that the respondent has wrongly withheld <lb/>a sum of Rs.59,60,127.50. <lb/>6. <lb/>The petitioner further avers that several request letters were <lb/>served on the respondent. This being letters dated 16.4.2015, 2.9.2015 <lb/>and 30.5.2016. <lb/></body>

			<note place="headnote">ARB. P. 545/2018 <lb/></note>

			<page>Page 3 of 3 <lb/></page>

			<body>7. <lb/>The petitioner also claims that since a notice dated 10.6.2016 <lb/>triggering the arbitration agreement was served on the respondent and, <lb/>therefore the claim is within limitation. <lb/>8. <lb/>Learned counsel for the respondent, on the other hand, raises <lb/>objections on the ground that since the instant petition was filed on <lb/>2.6.2018, the claim is barred by limitation. <lb/>8.1 According to me, prima facie, this submission is unsustainable. <lb/>9. <lb/>However, given the fact that there is no dispute as to the existence <lb/>of an arbitration agreement, I am inclined to allow the prayer. <lb/>10. Accordingly, Ms. Ravinder Kaur, (Cell no.:9910384660), former <lb/>District &amp; Sessions Judge, is appointed as the Arbitrator. <lb/>11. Since both the counsel are agreed that the arbitration proceedings <lb/>should be held under the aegis of the Delhi International Arbitration <lb/>Centre (in short &apos;Centre&apos;), it is ordered accordingly. <lb/>11.1 Consequently, the rules and the fee schedule of the Centre would <lb/>apply in this case. <lb/>12. The petition is disposed of in the aforesaid terms. <lb/>13. The Registry is directed to despatch a copy of this order to the <lb/>Co-ordinator, DIAC and the learned Arbitrator. <lb/>RAJIV SHAKDHER <lb/>(JUDGE) <lb/>DECEMBER 04, 2018 <lb/>rb </body>


	</text>
</tei>
